Rakib Raihan Fahim

**** +880 1305 642 784

☑ rfahim098@gmail.com

https://github.com/RyanFahim

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/rrfahim/

Panasree, Dhaka



CAREER OBJECTIVE

Persistent, detailed-oriented, and enthusiastic engineer having expertise over linux, penetration testing, vulnerabilities assessment and developing ERP systems in Python/Odoo on a large scale. Highly motivated to join an organization to enhance skills and strengthen knowledge in the related field, along with contributing to the growth of the organization.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Ultra-X BD

June 2022 - Present

Responsible For

- Software Development
- Software evaluation and testing
- Research and inspect technology.

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant at East West University

January 2019 - July 2021

Responsible For

- Assisting teachers with lesson preparation by getting materials ready and setting up equipment.
- Revise lesson material with students individually or in small groups.
- Document student progress

PROJECTS

Drutology: A new system to measure customer's experience in Bangladesh | github.com/RyanFahim/Drutology Key responsibilities of the project:

A mobile application developed with Android Studio to capture network parameters to provide a good network experience that can capture network signal value and user's location, measure download speed in that specific area and store it into a central database. Propose a decent and efficient way to analyze the network type and download speed in a particular area.

Student Result Management System | github.com/RyanFahim/Student-Result-Management-System Key responsibilities of the project:

A system developed with PHP that manages the details of result, activity, courses and exam and result.

Human Resource Management System | github.com/RyanFahim/HRMS

Key responsibilities of the project:

A system developed with Django that is used to manage human resources and related processes throughout the employee lifecycle.

Handwritten Character Recognition with Motion Detection |

github.com/RyanFahim/Handwritten-Character-Recognition-with-Motion-Detection Key responsibilities of the project:

A system developed with MAchine Learning that can identify characters using motion detection.

A 3D house computer graphics | github.com/RyanFahim/A-3D-house-computer-graphics-

Key responsibilities of the project:

A project developed with C/C++ with a 3D house view.

Jarvis, a simple AI | github.com/RyanFahim/Jarvis_a_simple_AI

Key responsibilities of the project:

A system developed with Python that can recognize voice and respond to the user's voice

Snake game | github.com/RyanFahim/Snake_game

Key responsibilities of the project:

A simple snake game developed by javascript. Can be played in pc

Live preview: https://snakegamebyfahim.netlify.app/

Weather App | github.com/RyanFahim/Snake_game

Key responsibilities of the project:

A simple weather app to search weather by city names developed by React JS

Live preview: https://weatherscan.netlify.app/

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Ethical Hacker | November 2021 - November 2024 . License ECC2615387094

COMPUTER SKILL

Programming Language: Python, C, C++, OOP, JavaScript

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL

Frameworks: Django

Operating System: Windows 7, 8.1 & 10, Android, Linux

Hardware: Comprehensive knowledge about computer hardware.

Interests: Networking, Cyber Security, Web Development

ACCOMPLISHMENT

Merit scholarship in East West University | January 2018 - January 2019 Dean's scholarship in East West University | January 2019 - January 2020

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

B.Sc. in Computer Science & Engineering | January 2017 - July 2021 | East West University

CGPA: 3.50 on a Scale of 4.00

Thesis: Drutology: A new system to measure customer's experience in Bangladesh

H.S.C from Science Group | March 2014 - July 2016 | Govt. Sundarban Adarsha College, Khulna

GPA: 4.75 on a Scale of 5.00

STRENGTH

Good analytical and problem-solving skill, Team player, and Strong interpersonal skills with a great work ethic.

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Bangla (Native), English (Proficient in communicating and writing)

REFERENCES

Ashikur Rahman

Territory Manager,

VMware Bangladesh

Email: rashikur@vmware.com Cell: +880 1713 201 885